<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="56"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[OUR




          VISION




          To actively contribute to the social and economic development of the
          underserved communities, lifting the burden of poverty and helping
          bring in inclusive growth. In so doing, build a better, sustainable way
          of life for the weaker sections of society and raise the country’s Human
          Development Index.




          GLIMPSES




          OF OUR WORK




          Jai Kisan – Farmer’s Widows’ Cause – Sun Foundation supported this cause in rehabilitating the widows’ families of the late
          debt-ridden farmers in the Vidharbha region by adopting and providing financial support to them.
          •  Supported launch of the movement ‘Roko Cancer’ through integrated mobile medical services.

          •  Instrumental in setting up of ‘Widows’ Child Fund’ for education of poor widows.
          •  Providing relief material at time of natural calamities (Uttarakhand, Nepal, etc.)

          Adopting children of Army Martyrs who laid their lives for the country.
          Having completed a journey or over two decades, Sun Foundation sees itself evolving in scale, depth and approach, to achieve
          greater impact in making meaningful differences in the lives for an equitable society.

          Sun Foundation has taken the initiative of commencement of a new program designed to help and train the youth to recruit in
          Indian Army.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[The future Soldiers of India will be provided FREE training to become eligible to join the Indian
          Army at Multi Skill Development Centre, Amritsar.

          The candidates with deep desire to honourably serve the country can now focus on academics
          and physical fitness desired to through rigorous training and meet the accession standards
          of the Indian Army.
          Sun Foundation works with a broad range of stakeholders to strengthen education system
          building blocks and address key barriers of education. We offer some of the key public health
          services which include:
          Trainings

          Skills Training: Sun Foundation is providing cutting edge content solutions to improve
          productivity for businesses and enhance employability.

          Ultimately, we:
          •  Transform the education system with new and innovative structure

          •  Emancipate talent by bridging gap between skills and knowledge
          •  Develop quality education and training aids

          Digital Training:

          Online (Through mobile and desktop): Sun Foundation aims to bridge the digital divide by
          providing economical education tablet PC. Some of the key features of digital training include:



          Through various initiatives, the Foundation has been helping bring about a direct positive
          change in the lives of children, youth, women and the physically challenged. The projects and
          campaigns that Sun Foundation has been engaged in:

              S. No         Name of initiative                             About the initiative

                                                      Providing free vocational and skill development
                1.      Surya Kiran
                                                      training for underprivileged women and girls.
                                                      Raising concerns about exacerbating sex
                2.      Save the Girl Child           discrimination and female foeticide through mass
                                                      awareness campaigns.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Free vocational and skill development training for
                                                        3.      Taare Zameen Par
                                                                                              differently abled youth.
                                                        4.      Angels of Sun                 Promoting education among needy children.

                                                                                              Launched drug de-addiction campaign with pledge
                                                                Drug De-addiction
                                                                                              by ~10, 000 youth against drug abuse in Amritsar.
                                                        5.      Campaign and
                                                                                              Conducting Rehabilitation and skill development
                                                                Rehabilitation
                                                                                              activities as well.
                                                                                              Adopting widows’ families of the farmers who
                                                                Jai Kisan – Farmer’s
                                                        6.                                    committed suicide in Vidarbha region through
                                                                widows’ Cause
                                                                                              financial support with direct credit to their banks.
                                                                                              Established Sikh Heritage Multimedia Museum at
                                                                Sikh Heritage                 Gurudwara Bangla Sahib, New Delhi depicting lives
                                                        7.
                                                                multimedia Museum             and times of the Sikh Gurus through paintings, murals
                                                                                              etc.

                                                                                              Adopted Shivkarwadi, a large slum in Versova and
                                                                Swachh Bharat                 Suvidha Chawl, Bhagat Singh Nagar, Goregaon (W),
                                                        8.
                                                                Abhiyan                       Mumbai for cleaning up the ground and well in the
                                                                                              compound and encouraged gardening.

                                                  Supporting

                                                  Jai Kisan – Farmer’s Widows’ Cause – Sun Foundation supported this cause in rehabilitating
                                                  the widows’ families of the late debt-ridden farmers in the Vidharbha region by adopting and
                                                  providing financial support to them.

                                                  •  Supported  launch  of  the  movement  ‘Roko Cancer’  through  integrated  mobile  medical
                                                     services.

                                                  •  Instrumental in setting up of ‘Widows’ Child Fund’ for education of poor widows.
                                                  •  Providing relief material at time of natural calamities (Uttarakhand, Nepal, etc.)

                                                  •  Adopting children of Army Martyrs who laid their lives for the country.

                                                  Having completed a journey or over two decades, Sun Foundation sees itself evolving in scale,
                                                  depth and approach, to achieve greater impact in making meaningful differences in the lives
                                                  for an equitable society.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Sun Foundation has taken the initiative of commencement of a new program designed to help and train the youth to recruit in
          Indian Army.

          The future Soldiers of India will be provided FREE training to become eligible to join the Indian Army at Multi Skill Development
          Centre, Amritsar.
          The candidates with deep desire to honourably serve the country can now focus on academics and physical fitness desired to
          through rigorous training and meet the accession standards of the Indian Army.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[PADMASHRI MR. VIKRAMJIT SINGH SAHNEY



          MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT – RAJYASABHA





          A self-made man and a true visionary, Vikramjit Sahney is a multifaceted personality playing many roles with panache. Reputed
          entrepreneur, philanthropist, educationist and social activist - he is a force to reckon with not just because of the success he has
          achieved but also because of his charismatic personality that is a motivation for many.

          GLOBAL FOOTPRINTS
          •      Former Chair, International Chamber of Commerce (ICC Paris-India)

          •      Former Chair, SAARC Chamber of Commerce & Industry (SAARC CCI)

          •      Member, Prime Minister’s India-Africa Business Council (IABC)

          •      Member, World Economic Forum (WEF)

          •      Association with BRICS

          •      National Executive Member, Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI)

          •      Council Member, International Fertilizer Industry Association (IFA)]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[His mantra of life - work is worship and charity is path to nirvana - is truly elucidated in supporting
                                                 the noble cause of saving the girl child.
                                                 A self-made man born in a small town of Kotkapura in Punjab with very humble beginnings,
                                                 went to an ordinary government school and government Barjindra College Faridkot and Punjabi
                                                 University Patiala and rose upto a renowned Global Punjabi , Philanthropist, Educationist and
                                                 Social Activist.

                                                 Shri Sahney has been conferred with one of the highest civic honour of Padma Shri by the
                                                 Hon’ble President of India for his extraordinary contribution towards the welfare of society at
                                                 large.

                                                 WORLD PUNJABI ORGANISATION

                                                 Vikram Sahney is founder and International President of World Punjabi Organisation (WPO)
                                                 is a non-political organisation set up in 1998 with Shri I.K. Gujral, the then Prime Minister of India
                                                 as its Patron-in-Chief to unite vast Punjabi NRI community with main stream of India and to
                                                 promote our rich cultural heritage. Mr. Sahney undertook various significant projects as under:








          Produced and staged mega light & sound shows - “Bole So Nihal” on tercentenary of Khalsa,
          Sher-e-Punjab Maharaja Ranjit Singh, Guru Maneo Granth, Sarbansdani Guru Gobind Singh Ji.
          These shows travelled all over the globe to preach rich history, cultural heritage and message of
          peace and harmony of the great Gurus.

          Mr. Sahney’s socio-cultural interests are very far-reaching. He has launched World Forum for
          Parliamentarians of Indian origin with over 50 parliamentarians as its members from all over the
          world. He organised World Punjabi conferences in Dubai, London, New York, Thailand, Singapore to
          unite NRI community with the main-stream of India. He commemorated of Important events like
          300 years birth of Khalsa and 350th Birthday of Shri Guru Gobind Singh Ji at National, International
          levels by organising various functions.

          He was instrumental in Installing an equestrian statue of Sher-e-Punjab Maharaja Ranjit Singh
          in the Parliament House.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[SIKH HERITAGE MULTIMEDIA MUSEUM
          Mr. Sahney has also set up Baba Bagel Singh Sikh Heritage Multimedia Museum at Gurudwara Bangla Sahib showcasing the rich
          history of Sikh culture and the sacrifices by this brave community for its motherland. The museum was inaugurated by Hon’ble
          Finance Minister Shri Arun Jaitley and has been visited by over 25 lakh visitors in just 3 years.

          He is Founder of Guru Tegh Bahadur Multimedia Auditorium and first ever Holographic Show of the life story of the Guru Tegh
          Bahadur Ji at Rakabganj Gurudwara near parliament house.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[SUN FOUNDATION, NGO

          Mr. Sahney has embarked his NGO upon a journey to create a
          humane and more equitable society through Sun Foundation
          reaching out to incapacitated and has provided support to less-
          privileged section of society.




















                                                                                 CORONA WARRIOR

                                                                                 With the unprecedented toll that the second wave has taken on the
                                                                                 country’s health infrastructure, its impact is being felt profoundly on
                                                                                 every aspect of life. Mr. Vikramjit Singh Sahney rendered exemplary
                                                                                 service to the under privileged and destitute during covid first and
                                                                                 second wave by donating oxygen plants, ECMO Machine, 1000
                                                                                 oxygen  concentrators,  2000  oxygen  cylinders  to  various  districts
                                                                                 and rural areas of Punjab.

                                                                                 He was Instrumental in setting up of a 400- bed Covid Care
                                                                                 Centre at Gurdwara Rakab Ganj in Delhi by providing 400 oxygen
                                                                                 concentrators free of charge. 500 additional oxygen concentrators
                                                                                 were donated to several districts of Punjab and various covid care
                                                                                 camps.  Oxygen  Concentrator  banks  were  set  up  all  over  Punjab
                                                                                 in collaboration with local Gurdwaras, Golden Temple Amritsar,
                                                                                 various Red Cross Societies and District Administrators.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[SKILLING YOUTH AND JOB ASSISTANCE

          Sun Foundation has set up World Class Skill Centres at ITI Campus, Jail Road, New Delhi and Amritsar. This multi skilling centres,
          with international standards, imparts World Class Skill courses free of charge for Indian/global needs supported by Industry. The
          Centres are providing skills to over 2000 students per year. Youth skilled at these centres are given job letter immediately after
          completion of courses. Evacuation and Rehabilitation of Afghan Refugees Mr. Sahney single handily sent 3 chartered flights at
          his own expense to Kabul to evacuate over 500 Afghani Hindu & Sikhs. He started a programme “My Family My Responsibility”
          for their rehabilitation in West Delhi by paying for their household expenses & Medical Health Insurance. He is also providing free
          skill training to these Afghan refugees through his NGO, Sun Foundation.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[DRUG DE-ADDCITION AND REHABILITATION

          Mr.  Sahney  is  running  Swami Vivekanand  Drug De-addiction
          & Rehab Centre in Amritsar, Punjab for purpose of drug de-
          addition and rehabilitation of Punjabi youth. The youth is being
          given various skills to empower them to earn their livelihoods
          apart from teaching them yoga, music, sports activities, gym
          and moral based education.

          Mr. Sahney organized the biggest campaign in Punjab with
          pledge by 10,000 youth against drug abuse at Amritsar by saying
          “No to Drugs”. International Footprints Mr. Sahney represented
          India in various International conferences like BRICS, IBSA i.e.
          India-Brazil-South  Africa,  SAARC,  BIMSTEC,  INDIA-ARAB  and  so
          on.

          Mr. Sahney has been the champion of Interfaith and Universal
          brotherhood and have hosted many functions in UAE, London
          and India for this cause.









                                                                                                                SUFI SINGER

                                                                                                                He is a passionate sufi singer. To his credit
                                                                                                                are  over  50  sufi  and  devotional  songs
                                                                                                                sung with famous Bollywood singers like
                                                                                                                Harshdeep Kaur, Nooran sisters, daughter
                                                                                                                of famous legendary singer Reshma
                                                                                                                to propagate the message of love and
                                                                                                                affection among human mankind and
                                                                                                                highlighting rich culture and heritage.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[AWARDS & ACCOLADES

          He has also been conferred with International Peace Award by the former President of Mauritius Anerood Jugnauth in New Delhi,
          Leadership Award from Mr. Hardeep Puri, Indian Ambassador & Permanent representative of India to United Nation, Raja Ram
          Mohan Roy Award for Women Upliftment, Rashtriya Gaurav Award, Mother India International Award, India Community Services
          Award, Momento by Sir Edmund Hillary and several others.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[WORLD CLASS SKILL CENTRE




          NEW DELHI





          Sun Foundation is consistently working towards its mission of imparting technical training to the needy and underprivileged and
          to encourage curiosity and innovativeness among the students to acquire quick learning ability and adaptive learning with the
          fast-changing needs of the industry.

          It is with this pledge, Sun Foundation has been mandated by DTTE (Dept. of Training and Technical Education) Govt. of NCT
          of Delhi to run World Class Skill Centre at ITI Campus, Jail Road, New Delhi. This multi skilling centre, with international
          standards, imparts world class skill courses for Indian/ global needs supported by Industry.

          Sun Foundation has created a benchmark for vocational training by making them relevant to industry and demand driven. The
          Foundation is driven to make a difference by preparing the prestigious national asset of the country - YOUTH towards “institution
          creation” rather than “infrastructure creation”. Our vision is to provide world class skills to the youth of India by imparting world
          class training, training technologies and world class physical environment. We are proud to say that the students skilled at the
          institute shall be valued assets of the country who are qualified for global opportunities as well.

          The Foundation comprises of highly energetic and dynamic team lead by its Chairman, CEO, Director and well qualified faculty
          members to enhance the quality of teaching and training of students. This is done with in-depth teaching, industrial visits,
          training seminars, conferences and expert lectures to prepare them for opportunities that await them.

          WCSC, Jail Road offers World Class Industry based hands-on skill training in various streams listed here:


                                 •  Web Developer                                   •  Domestic DEO

                                 •  Junior Software Developer                       •  Graphic Design

                                 •  Assistant Designer - AHF                        •  Assistant Beauty Therapist
                                 •  Field Engineer – RACW                           •  Draughtsman – Interior Designer

                                 •  Solar Panel Installation Technician             •  General Duty Assistant - Advance]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[In addition to this, the centre offers Program on Computer Data Application, soft skill & personality development for all its
         students to be able to communicate and connect with the industry with confidence and without any hurdle.
         The centre has the capacity of training approximately 1600 candidates per year (800 candidates per six months). Apart from
         state-of-the-art teaching-learning infrastructure like latest computer systems, smart classrooms, the campus would also have
         other recreational activities, tea/coffee/soup at no charge.

         EVENTS, CELEBRATIONS AND ACTIVITIES AT WCSC

         Japanese Delegates visited WCSC to meet GDAA trainees to guide them for their internship in JAPAN.

         The Japanese delegate visited the WCSC and organised a workshop for the GDA-A (Healthcare Sector) candidates to guide
         them towards the healthcare sector’s advancement in Japan. The members of delegate convinced the candidates for upskilling
         to get jobs in Japan.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Visit of LIONS Club Delegates at WCSC

          Loins Club delegates visited WCSC to meet the candidates of
          all the job roles. The delegates inspired candidates towards
          their social responsibilities.















          Ganesh Chaturthi: AFD trainees made beautiful ‘Ganesh Idols’


























                                                                           Ganesh Chaturthi was celebrated at World Class Skill Centre by the staff
                                                                           and candidates. The given sculptures were prepared by the candidates
                                                                           of Assistant Designer - Fashion, Home and Made-ups.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Vaccination Camp

          A vaccination drive was arranged
          at the campus of World Class Skill
          Centre against COVID for the staff
          members and the candidates.
















          General Pre-admission Test of New Batches on 24th Aug





                                                                                                                      The general pre-addmission test was
                                                                                                                     held in March and April months for the
                                                                                                                    new batches candidates so that WCSC
                                                                                                                    can find and councel them for job roles
                                                                                                                                 which most suitable to them.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Books Distribution Drive for New Batches
          The Book Distribution Drive is held everytime during
          the new batch commencement and the same was
          done in the month of April. The drive was made
          successful with the distribution of books in digital
          and physical formats.


















         Job Fair organized at WCSC























                                                                                                    WCSC organised job fair at its campus where more
                                                                                                    than 20 companies participated and around 450
                                                                                                    candidates appeared for the interview session.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Glimpses from the Interview Session in the Job Fair  at WCSC                     Mobilization]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Learning on the Go

          WCSC  is  running with 10  job roles  consisting  of
          modern labs and classrooms. After pre-addmission
          test and counselling, candidates go through the
          theory sessions in the classrooms as well as the
          practical in the labs. Trainers at WCSC work very
          hard  towards  content  delivery.  They  try  to  give
          hands-on practical knowledge to their candidates
          on the specific topics related to their courses. WCSC
          provides the candidates with the 21st century skills.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Mr. T.C Rao an army veteran visited WCSC







                                                                                                  Mr. T.C Rao an army veteran visited WCSC to
                                                                                                  motivate the candidates getting vocational
                                                                                                  training here. Mr. Rao presented a book written by
                                                                                                  him ‘Career Mantra’ to the Deputy Director – WCSC,
                                                                                                  Mrs. Sirat Ohri.

                                                                                                  Mr. T.C Rao motivated our trainees on their career
                                                                                                  goal and how to achieve it.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[PLACEMENT STATUS
























































             WCSC trained 383 candidates in the July 22 session. Total 336 candidates were found eligible, passed the assessment
             done through SSCs and 97.30% candidates got placement in their specific profiles.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[WCSC team celebrated Balli Sir’s Birthday at his                                 WCSC has celebrated every moment of life and shared
           residence on 13th Oct’22                                                         there happiness  with everyone , some .. Social  media
                                                                                            posts designed by WCSC on these moments.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Education Minister of the Kingdom of Lesotho visited WCSC


















































                                                                                Hon. Prof. Dr. Ntoi Paul Rapapa, Minister of Education and Training of the
                                                                                Kingdom of Lesotho visited WCSC accompanied by Mr. Ratsiu Majara,
                                                                                Deputy Principal Secretory and Mr. Thabang Linus Kholumo, Charge
                                                                                d’ Affairs a.i. of the High Commision on 24th Nov, 2022 and interacted
                                                                                with the candidates very formally. Mr. ...................... discussed with the
                                                                                candidates about their career plans, 21st century skilling and their role
                                                                                in “Make in India”. He asked some general questions to the candidates
                                                                                and rewarded them with the Lesotho currency.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Appreciation Letter from the High Commission of the Kingdom of Lesotho]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[AFD trainees visited Crafts museum
                                                                                                               along with their trainer to explore more
                                                                                                               about Art and culture.

         ID trainees visited IIFF at Greater Noida


















































                                                                                      ID & GD trainers along with Placement team
                                                                                      visited ACE tech exhibition at Pragati Maidan.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Song Launch – Sikhar Duphera by Mr. Sahney and Ms. Hargun Kaur

         WCSC team begun this New Year 2023 with the mesmerizing voice of Mr. Vikramjit Singh Sahney Ji and Ms. Hargun kaur in the
         Earth Song – Sikhar Dupehra. One of the enjoyable song, becoming popular among the youth nowadays.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Mr Sahney and Ms Hargun Kaur meet Candidates of WCSC during the Projects Exhibition]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Plantation


          Saving Earth and plantation are interconnected efforts
          crucial for ensuring a sustainable future. By prioritizing
          environmental        conservation,      adopting       sustainable
          practices, and actively participating in plantation initiatives,
          we can protect our planet’s ecosystems, mitigate climate
          change, and secure a better future for generations to
          come. It is our collective responsibility to act now and save
          Earth for a harmonious coexistence with nature.

          Keeping these things as his motive, Mr. Saheny did
          plantation with Ms. Hargun Kaur at World Class Skill Centre.
          The team Sun Foundation planted more than 120 trees in
          the campus.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Mr. Sahney and Ms. Hargun Kaur


                                                                            interacted with Media Personnel


                                                                            after Song launch Ceremony and

                                                                            Plantation Drive]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Ms. Atasi Misra (Operation Head –North) from Groom India Salon and
          Spa Pvt. Ltd. visited WCSC






































          Ms. Atasi Misra, sharing her experience in the beauty and
          wellness sector with ABT trainees. She said:

          The beauty and wellness sector has gained significant popularity
          in recent years, driven by increasing consumer awareness and the
          desire for self-care and self-expression. The industry emphasizes
          the importance of embracing one’s individuality, self-confidence,
          and overall well-being. It promotes a holistic approach to beauty
          and wellness, considering physical, mental, and emotional aspects
          of an individual’s health.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[WCSC- Placement team providing sessions to the trainees and
          making them ready for their interviews.






















                                                                                              A Proud moment for AD-FHM trainees

                                                                                              Three of AD-FHM candidates got internship in Shahi
                                                                                              Export that furnished them for their future endevours.













          Certificate  distribution  of  Green  Diwali  and  Rangoli
          competition in all the job roles.

          WCSC csndidates celebrated the recent Deepawali
          and Green Diwali by using No Patakha, No Plastic, No
          Water Wasting and taking care of Mother Nature. The
          candidates of all the job roles at WCSC participated in
          the Rangoli Competetion and winners were awarded
          with certificates.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Annual Function and Sahney sir


            Birthday Celebration]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Cultural Activities

          Cultural activities in India reflect the rich and diverse
          heritage of the country, comprising a wide range of
          art forms, traditions, festivals, and practices. These
          activities play a significant role in preserving cultural
          identity, promoting social cohesion, and showcasing
          the artistic talents of the Indian people.

          At WCSC, candidates along with the professional
          performer, performed Ganesh Vandana, Dance,
          Bhangra and other dramatic acts during the annual
          function 2023.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Innauguration of Incubation Centre by Institute for Industrial Development (IID) at WCSC

         This momentous occasion of the inauguration of Incubation Centre by Mr. Kamal Bhola from Institute for Industrial Development
         marks the beginning of a new chapter in fostering innovation and supporting aspiring entrepreneurs at WCSC. The Incubation
         Centre will provide a nurturing ecosystem for creative minds, offering invaluable resources, mentorship, and networking
         opportunities. Everyone who were enjoying the annual funtion witnessed the birth of groundbreaking ideas and ventures that
         will shape the future of new career seekers and industries. This inauguration set the stage for an exciting journey towards
         entrepreneurial success and economic growth for WCSC candidates.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Donating Mobile Langar Van to Tera Tera

          Langa Seva

          Tera Tera Langar Sewa was started in 2019. It was an
          initiative of Mr. Harjeet Singh Sethi Ji. Tera Tera Langar
          Sewa has been engaged in a number of social welfare
          activities. This langar sewa has been started to help the
          needy people.

          Mr. Vikramjit Singh Saheny donated a mobile van to Tera
          Tera Langa Sewa and handed over the key to Mr Sethi on
          the ocasssion of the annual day 2023 celebrated at WCSC
          campus. The mobile van is assisting the Langar team to
          serve the needy people who are staying in remote area
          and the team was not able to connect them befor.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Happy Lohri from Team

         WCSC


         Lohri is not just about festivities, but
         also a time to express gratitude
         for the abundance in our lives. It
         is an occasion to appreciate the
         blessings we have received and to
         share our joy with those around us.
         As we exchange sweets, popcorn,
         and peanuts, we are reminded of
         the importance of community and
         the joy of giving.























                                                                                                        The team WCSC celebrated Punjabi and North
                                                                                                     Indian festival Lohri at WCSC campus. The team
                                                                                                      enjoyed bonfire and exchanged Gajjak, Rewadi
                                                                                                                                              and Moongfali.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Garima Greh

         Garima Greh, also known as Garima Gruh or Garima Griha, is a
         shelter home established by the Delhi government to provide
         a safe and supportive environment for transgender individuals.
         The primary goal of Garima Greh is to offer a place of refuge
         and rehabilitation for transgender people who may have faced
         discrimination, violence, or social exclusion.
























                                                                                                            Inauguration of ‘Garima
                                                                                                            Greh Training Centre’ by Mr.
                                                                                                            Prince Dhawan (IAS) - District

                                                                                                            Magistrate, West Delhi

                                                                                                            Sun Foundation setup labs for Transgenders
                                                                                                            at Garima Greh, Dabri Crossing Area, New
                                                                                                            Delhi. The centre is accredited and affiliated
                                                                                                            with B&WSSC running the Assistant Beauty
                                                                                                            Therapist course. There are more than 20
                                                                                                            candidates being trained at Garima Greh
                                                                                                            now.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[MoU between Sun Foundation and   Institute

          for Industrial Development (IID) for Incubation

          Centre Opening at WCSC


          Hon’ble Mr. Vikramajit Singh Sahney and Mr. Kamal Bhola from IID signed an MoU
          to open an Incubation Centre at WCSC for the betterment of WCSC candidates.
          The incubation centre is helping candidates toward beign a good entrepreneur
          and self employed.]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[District Magistrate visited WCSC




          Hon’ble District Magistrate - West Delhi, Mr. Prince Dhawan-IAS visited
          WCSC, Jail Road along with his team along with Mr. Asheesh Kumar SDM
          Rajauri Garden and Mr. Aditya Bhatt SDM (T) and motivated the candidates
          to  move  forward  towards  adopting  21st  Century  Skilling  System  and
          assured us that the District Administration of West Delhi is going to help
          us in Nirmal Chhaya’s Sanitary Napkins Project and in the placement
          of the candidates getting skilled at WCSC as well as in the mobilization
          of the  new  candidates. Mr. Dhawan visited the entire campus and
          appreciated the trainees work and their projects. He discussed with
          candidates about their goals and guided them for their career.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Life Skills Workshop at District

          Magistrate Office by Mrs.

          Satvinder Kaur


































                                                                                                       Mrs. Satvinder (Life Skill Coach) took a workshop
                                                                                                       at DM office on 6th April’23. Our respected deputy
                                                                                                       director Ms. Sirat Mam, accompanied her along
                                                                                                       with other staff.

                                                                                                       Hon’ble DM Sir and his entire staff attended the
                                                                                                       workshop actively, and he appreciated Mrs.
                                                                                                       Satvinder’s & WCSC for all the efforts.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[5k Marathon organised by WPO

          World Punjabi Organisation and Vikramjit Singh Sahney
          hosted Vaisakshi Super Sikh 5K Marathon at Connaught
          Place in Delhi. With over 2,000 participants, the event
          saw the oldest marathon runner Fauja Singh, who is 112
          years old, flagging off the event. “The theme of the event
          was - Say No To Drugs,” said the organisers. The event
          concluded with Punjab’s signature colourful bhangra and
          spirited martial art gatka. The event was organised by
          Sun Foundation.







































          Shri Fauja Singh, also known as the Turbaned Tornado, also participated Vaisakshi Super Sikh 5K Marathon at Connaught
          Place in Delhi and motivated the participants toward healthy lifestyle. Fauja Singh is a British Sikh and retired marathon runner
          of Punjabi Indian descent. He has beaten a number of world records in multiple age brackets, but none of his times have been
          ratified as records.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[9th International Day of Yoga 21st June, 2023


         Sun Foundation commemorated a special event on International
         Yoga Day at WCSC where staff and the candidates experienced the
         benefits of yoga by promoting holistic health and inner peace.

         Highlights:


         •  Guided yoga session by experienced instructors

         •  Asanas (poses) and pranayama (breathing exaercises)

         •  Talks, demonstrations, and interactive workshops

         •  Connect with like-minded individuals]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Yoga is an ancient Indian practice that
                                                                                                            The International Day of Yoga is a global
          combines       physical      postures,      breathing
                                                                                                            observance celebrated on June 21st
          exercises, meditation, and ethical principles. It
                                                                                                            each year. It was established  by the
          is not only a form of exercise but also a holistic
                                                                                                            United Nations General Assembly in 2014
          approach to achieving harmony and balance
                                                                                                            to  recognize  and  promote  the  ancient
          in  one’s  life.  Yoga  helps  improve  flexibility,
                                                                                                            practice of yoga. The day aims to raise
          strength, and posture, while also reducing
                                                                                                            awareness  about  the  numerous  benefits
          stress, anxiety, and promoting mental clarity.
                                                                                                            of yoga for physical, mental, and spiritual
                                                                                                            well-being.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[MJULTI-SKILL DEVELOPMENT CENTRE




         AMRITSAR, PUNJAB









         Multi-skill Development Centre, set up at Amritsar opposite Guru Nanak Dev University. In addition to the courses offered in Delhi,
         the centre at Amritsar offers courses in Food &Beverage Steward, Sales Executive as well.

         Sun Foundation plans to open three more world class skill centres for imparting free skills to the youth and assist them in getting
         jobs.




















                                 •  Home Health Aids                                •  DDEO

                                 •  Food And Beverage Steward                       •  Assistant Electrician

                                 •  Field Sales Executive                           •  Welder Arc

                                 •  Fitter-Mechanical Assembly                      •  Multi Skill Technician - Food Processing

                                 •  Customer Care Executive                         •  Self-Employed Tailor]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Activities at MSDC


          Blood is the most precious gift that anyone can give to another person – the
          gift of life. Multi Skill Development Centre, Amritsar organized Blood Donation
          Camp by on 21 April 2023 for saving lives of people.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Guest Lectures





















          Motivation lecture given by HR Mr. Anurag Soni of Taj Swarna, Amritsar in MSDC Amritsar on 27 April 2023. They
          provide students with alternative perspectives, opinions, and their personal experiences that can reinforce the teachings
          of the instructor.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Baisakhi


         Baisakhi, a spring harvest festival of Punjab is celebrated on April 14 in MSDC, Amritsar.
         •  Worthy MLA Dr. Jasbir Singh grace the occasion as a Chief Guest.

         •  The New 14 batches are launched on the day of celebration.

         •  Prizes for the different competitions organized in MSDC, Amritsar from time to time were distributed by the honorable MLA
             saab.]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Placement at Hotel Taj Swarna


          9 Trainees of MSDC, Amritsar secured on role positions in
          hotel Taj Swarna, Amritsar after completion of one year
          internship.


          Sun foundation organized  International

          Job       Fair       Registration            Camp           with
          collaboration of NSDC

          Mr. Sandeep singh Kaura ji (Advisor Skill Development,
          Govt of India )and Padma shri Vikramjit singh Sahney ji
          (Sun Foundation Chairman)  along with team from NSDC
          and DPMU grace the occasion.

          On this Event the Successfully certified Trainees of MSDC,
          Amritsar received Certificates.

          Candidates of different trades from different areas
          participated  by registering  themselves in registration
          camp for foreign placements.














                                                                                     Sun foundation successfully got project from the Department of
                                                                                     Social Security, Women and Child Development, Government of
                                                                                     Punjab to provide training to 50 students in Domestic Data Entry
                                                                                     Operator job role. The target group will be below poverty line
                                                                                     and women basically.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Lady Noyce -


          Skilling for Deafs


          and Mutes
























                                                                                                                             Lady Noyce Senior Secondary
                                                                                                                             School for Deaf and Dumb at
                                                                                                                             Ferozshah Kotla New Delhi
                                                                                                                             is running in association
                                                                                                                             with Govt of NCT of Delhi.
                                                                                                                             Sun     Foundation       is    has
                                                                                                                             established a centre for
                                                                                                                             the students of Lady Noyce
                                                                                                                             School to educate them in
                                                                                                                             Information Technology and
                                                                                                                             Textile sector. Sun Foundation
                                                                                                                             is    providing       vocational
                                                                                                                             training to the students in
                                                                                                                             two job roles approve by
                                                                                                                             NSDC i.e. Domestic Data Entry
                                                                                                                             Operator and Taxtile.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Government Observation Home Boys,


          Mathura                                                           Sun Foundation


                                                                               is running
                                                                            another centre
                                                                            at Government
                                                                              Observation
                                                                               Home Boys
                                                                             Mathura. The
                                                                             resident of the
                                                                              observation
                                                                            home are being
                                                                           trained in two job
                                                                            roles i.e. Mobile
                                                                             Phone Repair
                                                                               Technician
                                                                              and LED Bulb
                                                                              Assembling
                                                                               Technician]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Krishna Kutir


         Krishna Kutir was inaugurated by UP Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath and Women and Child Development Minister Maneka Gandhi
         for. Sun Foundation started vocational training centre with two job roles which are Packer and Sewing Machine Operator. Both of
         the courses are making the women residing at Krishna Kutir self dependent and taking them towards self employment]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Nari Niketan and


                                                                                                      Short Stay Home &


                                                                                                                    Widow Home





























                                                                            Sun Foundation is serving the widows, girls and women residing at Nari
                                                                         Niketan and Short Stay Home situated at Nirmal Chhaya Parisar, Tihar Jail
                                                                         Complex, New Delhi. Sun Foundation facilitated Nari Niketan with Sanitary
                                                                             Pads making machine which is helping the girls staying there with the
                                                                       financial support. Sun Foundation is providing the women and widows with
                                                                                                the traning on stitching and lifestyle products making.]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>